zulip.org 2019-05-23

# Zulip: the best group chat for open source projects

As you use our services, we want you to be clear how we’re using information.

Our Privacy Policy explains:

  * What information we collect and why we collect it.
  * How we use that information.

## Information we collect

We collect information to provide better services to all of our users.

We collect information in two ways:

  * **Information you give us.** For example, many of our services require you to sign up for a Kandra Labs Zulip Account. When you do, we’ll ask for personal information, like your name, email address, or telephone number.

  * **Information we get from your use of our services.** We may collect information about the services that you use and how you use them, like when you interact with our content. This information includes:

    * **Device information.** We may collect device-specific information (such as your hardware model, operating system version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information including phone number). Kandra Labs may associate your device identifiers or phone number with your Kandra Labs Zulip Account.
    * **Log information.** When you use our services or view content provided by Kandra Labs, we may automatically collect and store certain information in server logs. This may include:

      * details of how you used our service.
      * Internet protocol address.
      * device event information such as crashes, system activity, hardware settings, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and referral URL.
      * cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your Kandra Labs Zulip Account.
    * **Unique application numbers.** Certain services include a unique application number. This number and information about your installation (for example, the operating system type and application version number) may be sent to Kandra Labs when you install or uninstall that service or when that service periodically contacts our servers, such as for automatic updates.

    * **Local storage.** We may collect and store information (including personal information) locally on your device using mechanisms such as browser web storage (including HTML 5) and application data caches.

    * **Cookies and anonymous identifiers.** We use various technologies to collect and store information when you visit our Zulip service, and this may include sending one or more cookies or anonymous identifiers to your device. We may also use cookies and anonymous identifiers when you interact with services we offer to our partners, such as Zulip features that may appear on other sites.

## How we use information we collect

We use the information we collect from all of our services to provide, maintain, protect and improve them, to develop new ones, and to protect Kandra Labs and our users.

We may use the name you provide for your Kandra Labs Zulip Account across all of the services we offer that require an account. In addition, we may replace past names associated with your account so that you are represented consistently across all our services. We may show other users your publicly visible account information, such as your name.

When you contact Kandra Labs, we may keep a record of your communication to help solve any issues you might be facing. We may use your email address to inform you about our services, such as letting you know about upcoming changes or improvements.

We use information collected from cookies and other technologies to improve your user experience and the overall quality of our services.

We may combine personal information from one service with information, including personal information, from other Kandra Labs services.

Kandra Labs processes personal information on our servers in many countries around the world. We may process your personal information on a server located outside the country where you live.

## Accessing and updating your personal information

Whenever you use our services, we aim to provide you with access to your personal information. If that information is wrong, we strive to give you ways to update it quickly or to delete it – unless we have to keep that information for legitimate business or legal purposes. When updating your personal information, we may ask you to verify your identity before we can act on your request.

We may reject requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort (for example, developing a new system or fundamentally changing an existing practice), risk the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes).

Where we can provide information access and correction, we will do so for free, except where it would require a disproportionate effort. We aim to maintain our services in a manner that protects information from accidental or malicious destruction. Because of this, after you delete information from our services, we may not immediately delete residual copies from our active servers and may not remove information from our backup systems.

We do not share personal information with companies, organizations and individuals outside of Kandra Labs unless one of the following circumstances apply:

  * **With your consent.** We will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Kandra Labs when we have your consent to do so. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any sensitive personal information.

  * **With domain administrators.** If your Kandra Labs Zulip Account is managed for you by a domain administrator then your domain administrator and resellers who provide user support to your organization will have access to your account information (including your email and other data). Your domain administrator may be able to:

    * view statistics regarding your account.
    * change your account password.
    * suspend or terminate your account access.
    * access or retain information stored as part of your account.
    * receive your account information in order to satisfy applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.
    * restrict your ability to delete or edit information or settings.

Please refer to your domain administrator’s privacy policy for more information.

  * **For external processing.** We provide personal information to our affiliates or other trusted businesses or persons to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy.

  * **For legal reasons.** We will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Kandra Labs if we, in our sole discretion, determine that that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is necessary to:

    * meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.

    * enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations.

    * detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.

    * protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Kandra Labs, our users or the public as required or permitted by law.

We may share aggregated, non-personally identifiable information publicly and with our partners. For example, we may share information publicly to show trends about the general use of our services.

We may share personal information in connection with an acquisition, merger, or sale of all or a substantial portion of our business, with or to another company. In any such event, you will receive notice if your data is transferred and becomes subject to a substantially different privacy policy.

## Application

Our Privacy Policy applies to all of the services offered by Kandra Labs, Inc. and its affiliates, including services offered on other sites, but excludes services that have separate privacy policies that do not incorporate this Privacy Policy.

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by other companies or individuals, sites that may include Zulip services, or other sites linked from our services. Our Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of other companies and organizations who advertise our services, and who may use cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to serve and offer relevant ads.

## Data Protection Officer

To communicate with our Data Protection Officer, please email data-protection-officer@zulipchat.com.

See the article on Zulip's GDPR compliance for details on how Kandra Labs and Zulip comply with the General Data Protection Regulation.

## Changes

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will post the latest version of our privacy policy on this page.

Last modified: May 24, 2018
